Date: 2023-03-13 +46 705 86 94 08 staffan.bjornson@toor.se



Staffan Björnson CV

One of my life mottos are:

" If you ever start taking things too seriously, just remember that we are talking monkeys on an organic spaceship flying through the universe."

Test Automation Evangelist and automation work flows.

I have a diverse background in test and QA, both for software and hardware. I have extensive experience and expertise in test automation. I have gained my skills by building test frameworks with focus on mainlines and integration of automation into a agile software development life cycle. During my career, I have successfully identified test scenarios that are best suited for automation and the knowledge to when manual testing is more effective.

Kompetenser i fokus: Test & verification, Automation, Test data management, Agile work flow, CI/CD, Linux/*nix, Robot Framework, HSM, POS terminal verification

Assignment in focus

Test Automation Specialist — Tele2 Working as a test automation specialist in quality refinement and requirement gathering. I implement and drive test automation and CI/CD initiatives in cooperation with the development teams.

Experience

PwC

2022 – Now Stockholm, Sweden

Test Specialist/Test Automator

Developed and implemented a automated test framework for a customer specific application that ran in an Azure DevOps environment.

Tasks

- Creating automated API tests
- Manage manual test suites
- Worked closely with developers to develop unit tests
- Developed an agile testing strategy
- Drove the agile way of working

Test Automation

Creating a automated test framework and rewrite manual test to automated ones in close collaboration with the developers, BA, and PO. Introduced Robot Frameworks for a total automation suit in combination with Gherkins "Given-When-Then" format. Technical know-how for the development of automated tests, primary with Robot Frameworks and Python. Convert manual test suites, weed out old or ineffective tests, and finding a achievable way of approaching automation.

Test Automation, Test data management, Agile Work flow, Windows, DevOps Azure, React, Python, Gherkin, Selenium, Robot framework, Git, Docker, API-testing,

Tele₂ AB

2019 – Dec 2022 Stockholm, Sweden

Test Automation Specialist

Working as a test automation specialist in quality refinement and requirement gathering. I implement and drive test automation and CI/CD initiatives in cooperation with the development teams.

Tasks

- CI/CD implementation
- Test Strategy development
- Agile Work Flow implementation
- Education in agile methodology
- Manual to automation conversion

Test Automation Specialist

As a member of the CI/CD team, the test specialist's job is to evaluate the development teams to be able to automate and become CI/CD. Creating specific test strategies for different development teams within Tele2 to facilitate and enhance the testing process.

Test Automation

An important part of the assignment was to identify the needs of the development teams and find a framework that works for the teams when they need to automate. Part of the assignment was to hold courses in what you need to consider when implementing automation and potential pitfalls.

Requirements analysis/Test management

I identify shortcomings in the quality process, an overall test strategy was created for Tele2 that was implemented. Part of this work was to hold QA forums for test automation for mainly QA, PO and other stakeholders at Tele2 where we went through new innovations, how to must think, what is "best practice" etc.

Test Automation, Test data management, Agile Work flow, CI/CD, Linux/*nix, Windows, DevOps Azure, React, Python, Gherkin, Selenium, Robot framework, RPA, Cypress, Git, Docker, Kubernetes, Kibana, Jira, Confluence, TestRail, API-testing,

Kambi Group

2018 – Oct 2019 Uppsala, Sweden

Tester/Test lead

Test lead in autonomous agile team that delivered a odds calculation functions for sports betting.

Tasks

- Test manager
- Requirements in conjunction with stakeholders
- Manual System/exploratory testing
- Creating automated test (UAT and regression)

Tester

As a tester in an agile team I created test strategy and ran manual tests with focus on exploratory testing. I also started a team project to automate our regression tests within the team, based on Python and Robot Framework that was integrated with our deploy pipeline.

Test Automation, Test data management, Test & Verification, Agile Work flow, Linux/*nix, Java, Kotlin, React, Python, Gherkin, Selenium, Robot framework, Cypress, Git, Docker, Kibana, ELK stack, Grafana, Jira, Confluence, API-testing, Maven

Espland AB

2015 – Nov 2018 Uppsala, Sweden

Test lead/Jr Developer

As a tester and a developer for a TMS (POS-Terminal Management System) I manage testing and compliance with PCI DSS standards.

Tasks

- Software Testing
- Hardware Testing
- Compliance

- Java Development
- Support and Sales

Technical Tester

The role involved both work as a tester and junior developer within Java, in my role as test leader I had the main responsibility for ensuring that the tests of self-developed software including integrations to standard software have been carried out, both through automated and manual tests in which I participated in the work with tests. When delivering software updates to the customer, I participated in the customer's work with tests of the product through support and direct efforts in the customer's test environment.

If necessary, I worked as a resource-reinforced CAPSAB's team (Card and Payment Solution) with knowledge in verification and testing of payment terminals against both Swedish and international requirements.

Test Automation, Test data management, Test & Verification, Agile Work flow, Linux/*nix, Windows, Java, React, Python, Gherkin, Selenium, Robot framework, Cypress, Git, Docker, Kubernetes, Kibana, ELK stack, Grafana, Jira, Confluence, TestRail, Elastic Search, API-testing, Maven

Verifone

2011 – 2014 Uppsala, Sweden

Technical Tester/Test Environment Engineer

As a software and hardware tester I did manual tests but also built the test environments for our teams with integration with HMSs and third-party systems.

Tasks

- Software Testing
- Hardware Testing
- Compliance
- POS-Terminal

- Test Environment management
- Agile work flows
- Support and Sales

Technical Tester

I did manual acceptance test in close work with the developers (XP programming). We ware the first team at Verifone to work in a SCRUM configuration so a lot of work went in to finding a good and correct agile work flow.

At Verifone, I was responsible for their internal test environment from OS level up to test tools and integrations with HSM. Among other things He helped build a system to automatically deploy OS and software to test environments.

Test data management, Test & Verification, Agile Work flow, Linux/*nix, Windows, Java, Vaadin, Python, Gherkin, Selenium, Robot framework, Cypress, Git, Docker, Kubernetes, Kibana, ELK stack, Grafana, Jira, Confluence, TestRail, API-testing, Maven

Courses

DevOps 2023 Learn CI/CD Process for Professionals and Teams

DevOps and CI/CD is a mindset. Practices of CI/CD for Agile Teams, including tips for remote workers -2023

Elegant Automation Frameworks with Python and pyTest

Building a fast automation framework with minimal complexity that have actionable reporting using pyTest and Python. — 2023

Linux Security and Hardening, The Practical Security Guide.

Security concepts and guide lines for hardening Linux system security. -2020

Robot Framework Test Automation (Level 1-2 & Jenkins CI)

Automate complex interactions across multiple web applications. Integrate Robot Framework tests into a Jenkins CI pipeline. — 2018, 2019

Skills

Technical

- Robot Frameworks
- pyTest
- Selenium
- Linux

- Linux Security
- Windows
- Azure DevOps
- Analytical Skills

- Test Automation
- Test Planning
- Agile Methodologies
- Agile Testing

- Scrum
- System Testing
- Python

- Jenkins
- Red Hat Satellite
- FreeIPA

- Payment Gateways
- Selenium

Language

- Swedish
- English

Driving license

- A Motor cycle
- B Car

Social





GitHub github.com/StaffanOB/



Toor.se www.toor.se/